so yesterday i sat through a friend's
doterra essential oil pitch and i'm
gonna be sending her an own message by
itself
but i want to talk about the financial
compensation plan of doterra
of which i watched a youtube video i
will link in the comments
so this woman's talking about of course
how you can build your business and it's
so easy and it's just about the power of
three
i will also link to the timestamp she
goes over the first three kinds of
compensation which have problems in and
of themselves
but this is the big one this is why
people get involved in it so
all you have to do is recruit
three friends who recruit
three friends who recruit three friends
right down the line so this line the
three
you get two percent of everything they
sell they sell
the next line down you get three percent
of
and then five percent and then five
percent
and then six percent and then six
and then seven percent
this is already broken because this
means everything that is sold
has a 34 commission on it 34
that isn't going into making the product
better it isn't going the way they can
afford this is
all of this free labor so
34 is what you have to sell your
customers you're not selling a product
you're selling a business
so they have to be convinced that they
can also make this some mlms have this
flipped
so that you have the biggest amount up
here they are
better mlms still predatory still a
problem
but they can't convince you of what she
says next with this compensation plan
everybody's spending their 150 pv
basically 150
a month on product
you get 32 000
per month but what that means is
this line here is 2 1887 people
you have to convince three people to
convince three people to convince three
people
you have to dupe three people to duke
three people to duke three people
so that the total all seven lines down
is thirty two hundred and eighty people
involved selling a hundred and fifty
dollars a month of essential oils to
themselves
or loved ones that they're gonna dupe
into this because nobody needs 150
of essential oils a month month after
month that is how you get the 32 000
which means the vast majority of your
income if you actually
could do this comes from this line
2187 people spending 150
a month and you get seven percent of
that that number is 23 000
so most of that money comes from that
line
even if it's reversed the math is broken
but these people
the 3 280 people can't also build
3 280 people and even if they can
because you're not out of you know
you're still actually kind of in the
realm of possibility at that point but
even if they can
you definitely can't get more than two
layers down
these thirty two hundred and eighty
people becoming the first person and
themselves
including and recruiting thirty two
hundred and eighty people
that's 32 80 times 32 80. it's this
squared
even if that's possible because persona
you can't get to the third
you run out of humans we don't have
enough farmland to make that many
essential oils
we don't have enough people
mlms are broken they destroy
relationships
because of this math she did not break
it down
she doesn't say this number 3280 she
just gives you the total
not that you're living off of the labor
and connections
of this layer
please do not get involved in mlms do
not
buy from people who are involved in mlms
which is also this is not a business
this can be take even if you built this
even if it was ethical it can be taken
away from you at any time as soon as the
government catches wind of this and they
do
they usually do about you know one mlm a
year they're like wait this is broken
you need to you can't have any more than
this well
what are you gonna do no you don't earn
money now you're only earning two
percent three percent
even if they break that down right so
that i don't know
these people aren't only earning 15 and
these ones are owning
uh 19
you can't live off of that because it's
only three people in nine people
that's not getting you 32 000 a year
even with the same compensation it
requires broken math it requires this
exponential growth it requires
a freaking pyramid
in order for you to get rich and it's
not by selling product it's by selling
people this system
which is broken broken af
please pass this on to your friends and
family and stop
telling people you have a business
opportunity for them and what you're
doing is selling them bankruptcy
you